mmos.com 2002-08-02

# Pharmacia Corporation | Privacy Policy

Pharmacia Corporation privacy policy

To review definitions of key words, browse our glossary.

Pharmacia and your privacy

The Privacy of your personal information is important to Pharmacia. To better protect your privacy, we provide you with our Privacy Policy so that you will understand both our commitment to you and to your privacy. This Privacy Policy describes what information we may collect about you; how we use your information; how we protect it; and what choices you have on how that information is used. At Pharmacia, we understand that health is a very personal, private subject, and we want you to feel as comfortable as possible visiting our various websites and using their respective services.

Pharmacia is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. This statement discloses the privacy practices for this Pharmacia site. When you visit a website displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, you will be informed of the following: What personally identifiable information of yours is collected; what organization is collecting the information; How the information is used; with whom the information may be shared; what choices are available regarding collection, use and distribution of the information; what kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control; and, how you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact [privacy.officer@pharmacia.com](mailto:privacy.officer@pharmacia.com). If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe through the TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the website to resolve users' concerns.

Pharmacia also complies with the standards set by Health on the Net [HON], as is indicated by the presence of the seal.

As our privacy policies change in significant ways, we will make every effort to notify you of the changes. Minor changes to the policy may occur that will not affect our use of individually identifiable health information. When the privacy policies change in a way that significantly affects the way we handle personal information, we will not use the information we have previously gathered without obtaining your consent. We will post privacy policy changes on our websites in a timely manner.

When we refer to ourselves as "we" or "Pharmacia", we mean our entire company, including any company that we control (for example, a subsidiary that we own.) We may share information among our subsidiaries that we own or control, but it is always protected under the terms of this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy only applies to Pharmacia's websites. You should read the Privacy Policy at each website that you visit after you leave one of our sites. Pharmacia is not responsible for how other websites treat your privacy, once you leave a Pharmacia site.

The following Articles make up our Privacy Policy. We hope that reading them gives you a clear idea of how we manage information regarding you. For immediate access to a particular topic, click on the title of that topic.

**Personal information we collect.**

In this section of our Privacy Policy, we discuss the different types of information we may collect about you, and the ways in which we collect information.

**Information we collect from visitors**

Visitors to each of our websites can access the website's home page, and browse some areas of the site, without disclosing any personally identifiable information. We do track information provided to us by your browser, including the website you came from (known as the "referring URL"), the type of browser you use, the time and date of access, and other information that does not personally identify you. On some of our sites, you must register to access portions of the site.

In addition, we gather information about you that is automatically collected by our Web server, such as your IP address and domain name. Pharmacia may use this information to customize its offerings and presentations.

**Information we collect when you register**

Visitors registering for services on our websites are asked to provide identifying information, such as name, gender, contact information, etc. On the registration screen, we clearly label which information is required for registration, and which information is optional and may be given at your discretion. You will also be given a choice about whether or not you want to receive e-mail information. Pharmacia websites obtain visitors' consent before collecting personally identifiable information.

**Information from outside sources**

We may also collect information about physicians or other healthcare professionals who register on our websites from other sources in order to verify their licensure status and identity. In some cases, we ask customers for information after they register, such as credit card information. Where necessary (for example, to process an order for a purchase), our websites may contact financial or credit organizations to confirm customer credit card information.

**Other information**

•  We also collect information that you voluntarily provide to us through responses to surveys, questionnaires and the like.

•  When you are using a discussion or message board on our websites, you are posting a message and your user name, which is available for all registered users to see. You should not post any information you want to keep private to a discussion board or other public forum on our websites.

•  On some of our websites, we offer health assessment tools that ask you to provide self-assessment information.

•  We may also ask you to provide additional information such as your e-mail address if you want to obtain additional services or information or to resolve complaints or concerns.

**Use of cookies and other tracking systems**

Cookies and log files are technologies used by the Pharmacia websites to identify a user as the user moves through our websites. Your browser allows us to place some information on your computer's hard drive that identifies the computer you are using. We may use cookies to personalize our websites and to track your usage across other websites.

Your Web browser can be set to allow you to control whether you will accept cookies, reject cookies, or to notify you each time a cookie is sent to you. If your browser is set to reject cookies, websites that are cookie enabled will not recognize you when you return to the website, and some website functionality may be lost. The Help section of your browser will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting cookies.

On occasion, we contract with third parties to place Cookies on your computer's hard drive. These third parties have entered into an agreement with us that requires them to observe our Privacy Policy.

Although cookies do not normally contain personally identifiable information, if you have provided us information about you, we may associate your registration information with cookies our website places on your computer's hard drive. Associating a cookie with your registration data allows us to offer increased personalization and functionality. Without cookies, this functionality would not be possible.

Some of our business partners may use cookies on our site. (For example, links to business partners.) We do not want our business partners to use cookies to track our customers' activities once they leave our sites. However, we may not have total control over how our business partners may use cookies on our website. If you become aware that a Pharmacia business partner is placing an unwanted cookie on your hard drive, please contact our privacy officer to assist us in resolving the problem.

In addition, we may use other tracking systems. [For information see Web Bugs & Log Files]

**How we use the information**

In this section of our Privacy Policy, we identify the ways we may use information about you that we have collected.

**Aggregate data**

We create aggregate data about visitors to our websites for product development and improvement activities. We also use it for market analysis. We may provide information from our websites in aggregate form, with identifying information removed, to third parties. For example, we may tell a health care partner what percentage of our registered users reside in a particular geographical area. When aggregate health information is provided, we pool it from many individual records and strip it of any data that could be used to identify an individual before it is used. Any third party that receives aggregated healthcare data must agree not to attempt to re-identify the people it belongs to.

Depending on our agreement with the third parties, we may or may not charge for this information.

**Marketing**

We may target our marketing depending on information we have about you. For example, a user we know is a woman may receive information on products targeted at women that a male user will not see, or a user who we know is a healthcare professional who treats arthritis may receive information for new arthritis therapies. We may send information to you that we may believe will benefit you, including information about any Pharmacia product. [See your Privacy Choices for opt-out information]

We may also personalize our website based on your interests. For example, you may see different articles in different places on our website based on information you have shared with us, or information we have gained by reviewing your previous visits, or information we may have gained from your interactions with a third party that shares information with us.

When we share information with third parties, we use our best efforts to assure that they agree in writing to abide by Pharmacia privacy policies.

If we discover that a third party inappropriately disclosed personal information about any of our visitors, we will take immediate action to prevent further occurrences.

Other than as described above, Pharmacia will not release personally identifiable information to a third party without your consent. Also, if we ask your consent to release personal healthcare information to a third party, we will use our best efforts to clearly define and limit the scope of your consent.

**Protection of information**

**How Pharmacia handles privacy internally**

In this section of our Privacy Policy, we discuss the security measures we take to protect information that we have collected about you.

**Our commitment to security**

We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security and correctly use the information we collect online.

**General policies**

We have implemented technology and security policies, rules and other measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from unauthorized access, improper use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction, and accidental loss. We also protect your information by requiring that all our employees and others who have access to or are associated with the processing of your data, respect your confidentiality.

Pharmacia uses security methods to determine the identity of its registered users, so that appropriate rights and restrictions can be enforced for that user. Reliable verification of user identity is called authentication. Pharmacia uses both passwords and usernames to authenticate users. Users are responsible for maintaining their own passwords.

**Storage of health information**

Personally identifiable health information you share with us, or that we obtain through our relationship with other health care professionals, is stored on our database servers at Pharmacia data centers or hosted by third parties who have entered into agreements with us that require them to observe our Privacy Policy. We have a firewall and other technology to prevent individuals from accessing information without authorization. Data centers are physically secure and protected from unauthorized access by unauthorized persons.

Information in our data centers is backed up routinely, in order to aid in the recovery of information in the event of accidental damage of information or due to a natural disaster. The backup media is stored in a physically secure storage facility.

**Third parties**

In addition, to aggregate information (discussed previously), we may share some kinds of information with third parties as described below.

•   **Companies and people who work for us** : Because we are a large company, we contract with other companies and individuals to help us provide services. For example, we may host some of our websites on another company's computers, hire technical consultants to maintain our Web-based health sites, or work with companies to remove repetitive information from customer lists, analyze data, provide marketing assistance, and provide customer service. In addition, if you are a healthcare professional, we may validate your licensure status and other information against available databases that list licensed health care professionals. In order to perform their jobs, these other companies may have limited access to some of the personal information we maintain about our users. Other companies may collect information on our behalf through their sites. This occasionally incorporates the use of frames on the site that will not show the URL you are visiting in the browser address window. We require all such companies to comply with the terms of our privacy policies, to limit their access to any personal information to the minimum necessary to perform their obligations, and not to use the information they may access for purposes other than fulfilling their responsibilities to us. We use our best efforts to limit the use of other companies in areas where personally identifiable healthcare information may be involved.

•   **Promotional offers** : Sometimes we send offers to selected groups of customers on behalf of other businesses. When we do this, we do not give that business your name and address. We provide a variety of mechanisms for you to tell us you do not want to receive such promotional offers. For example, we may provide an opt-in box for customers to receive a coupon or information that is sent by a third party fulfillment house, and we make clear that, by opting in, you are submitting your data to a third party. You can elect to not receive promotional material from us by sending us an e-mail to: unsubscribe.program@pharmacia.com and identify such promotional offer.

•   **Business transfers** : If we transfer a business unit (such as a subsidiary) or an asset (such as a website) to another company, we will require them to honor the terms of this Privacy Policy.

•   **Legal requirements** : We may release account and other personal information when we believe release is required to comply with law. We may release personal health information, if, in our judgment after review by an attorney, the release is compelled by law or regulation, or if the release may be necessary to prevent the death or serious injury of an individual.

**Your privacy choices**

When you complete Registration of your Member Profile, you will be given the option of receiving recurring informational/promotional e-mails from Pharmacia and/or third parties. You may opt-out from receiving these e-mails when you provide the information at any time. We ask for contact information (such as, name and e-mail address) if you wish to request e-mail information. You can unsubscribe from such e-mails very easily. When you have received an e-mail you wish to stop, click on the "forward" button in your mail program, then send us an e-mail to: unsubscribe.program@pharmacia.com.

Customer Service will unsubscribe you from that newsletter within five (5) business days.

**Choice.** You will be given the opportunity to choose (opt-out) whether your personal information is (a) to be disclosed to a third party or (b) to be used for a purpose that is different from the purpose originally intended or authorized. In addition for sensitive information which includes personal information specifying medical or health conditions, you will be given an affirmative or explicit opt-in choice.

**Onward transfer.** (Transfers to Third Parties): Before we will disclose information to a third party, we will provide you with notice and choice before either personal information or sensitive information is transferred.

**Updating your personal information and contacting Pharmacia**

You can always contact us in order to (a) remove the Personal Information that you have provided to us from our systems, (b) update the Personal Information that you have provided to us, and (c) change your preferences with respect to marketing contracts, by emailing us at privacy.officer@pharmacia.com.

**Children's policy**

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. You should be aware that this Site is not intended or designed to attract children under the age of 13. We do not collect personally identifiable information from any person we actually know is a child under the age of 13.

Pharmacia Corporation Privacy Policy Updated November 16, 2001
